TRAIN_DATA = [
('One of the most prominent instances that made me realize the deep-seated educational disparities for minority and lower-income students occurred when I tested a 5th grade Philadelphia public school student named Jenna.',
  {'entities': [(1, 4, 'CARDINAL'),(162, 165, 'ORDINAL'),(172, 184, 'GPE'),(213, 218, 'PERSON')]}),
('Pursuing a Master’s degree in Sociology and Education at Teachers College will empower me to better support underserved students by gaining a comprehensive understanding of the U.S. education system, engaging with professors who are leaders in the field of urban education, and acquiring research skills that will enable me to critically analyze school systems from a sociological perspective.',
  {'entities': [(58, 74, 'ORG'), (178, 182, 'GPE')]}),
("My experience as a Posse Scholar at Bryn Mawr College and working in the education nonprofit sphere in Philadelphia has allowed me to interpret the education system from a number of diverse viewpoints.",
  {'entities': [(37, 54, 'ORG'), (104, 116, 'GPE')]}),
("After graduating Bryn Mawr College as a Posse Foundation Scholar, I recognized the transformative potential that a quality education has on the lives of students who are products of under-resourced school districts.",
  {'entities': [(18, 35, 'ORG'), (39, 65, 'ORG')]}),
("During my time at Bryn Mawr I took classes such as Race, Gender and Culture and The Black Self: Identity and Consciousness which dissected race and social identity from a perspective that allowed me to better understand systemic racism and how communities of color shape and mold their consciousness.",
  {'entities': [(21, 30, 'ORG'), (54, 58, 'ORG')]}),
("My entry into professional education began at Leading Educators, a nonprofit dedicated to identifying high quality teachers in the D.C. public school system for their Teacher Leadership Fellowship.",
  {'entities': [(49, 66, 'ORG'),(134, 138, 'GPE'),(170, 199, 'WORK_OF_ART')]}),
("My current position at For Love of Children (FLOC) involves supporting students like Jenna who are severely below grade level and have limited access to quality educational resources.",
  {'entities': [(30, 46, 'WORK_OF_ART'), (88, 93, 'PERSON')]}),
("As a Scholars Program Coordinator, I facilitate free after-school workshops on grade-based curriculum as well as postsecondary preparation for 8th and 11th grade students from the D.C. community.",
  {'entities': [(3, 36, 'WORK_OF_ART'),
                (146, 149, 'ORDINAL'),
                (154, 158, 'ORDINAL'),
                (183, 187, 'GPE')]}),
("Having the opportunity to attend and take courses at Teachers College with innovators such as Amy Stuart Wells truly excites me because of my admiration for her research on race and school desegregation.",
  {'entities': [(56, 72, 'ORG'), (97, 113, 'ORG')]}),
("In April 2016, I had the opportunity to hear Professor Wells speak at a seminar titled, Taking Action on School Diversity.",
  {'entities': [(6, 16, 'DATE'), (58, 63, 'PERSON'), (91, 124, 'ORG')]}),
("I am also eager to explore Professor Jeffrey Henig’s work on reforming urban schools and analyzing the intersections of race, politics, and education in urban environments.",
  {'entities': [(40, 53, 'PERSON')]}),
("Additionally, after speaking with several students currently in the Sociology & Education program and attending an open house, I can think of no institution more perfectly suited to my interests and ambitions.",
  {'entities': [(67, 92, 'ORG')]}),
("Paul Rusesabagina, the hero of the Hollywood blockbuster Hotel Rwanda, is not considered a \"rescuer\" in Rwanda nor in academic literature because, according to the Rwandan government, he made Tutsis pay to stay at the Hotel de Milles Collines.",
  {'entities': [(3, 20, 'PERSON'),(38, 47, 'GPE'),(60, 72, 'GPE'),(107, 113, 'GPE'),(167, 174, 'NORP'),(195, 201, 'NORP'),(217, 245, 'FAC')]}),
("Similarly vexing, there are very few \"Righteous Among the Nations\" from Denmark, despite 99% of Danish Jews surviving the Holocaust; the Danish Underground wanted to be seen as a communal movement, precluding them from the honor, which is only given to individuals.",
  {'entities': [(41, 68, 'WORK_OF_ART'),(75, 82, 'GPE'),(92, 95, 'PERCENT'),(99, 105, 'NORP'),(106, 110, 'NORP'),(125, 134, 'EVENT'),(136, 158, 'PRODUCT')]}),
("Much of the limited scholarship on rescuing during mass atrocities defines \"rescuers\" using stringent constraints set by Yad Vashem’s \"Righteous Among the Nations\" eligibility criteria: individuals must be non-Jewish and have (1) had active involvement in saving Jews; (2) risked their lives, liberty, or position; and (3) been only altruistically motivated.",
  {'entities': [(124, 134, 'PERSON'),(138, 165, 'WORK_OF_ART'),(209, 219, 'NORP'),(230, 231, 'CARDINAL'),(266, 270, 'NORP'),(273, 274, 'CARDINAL'),(323, 324, 'CARDINAL')]}),
("The Rwandan government supplements these criteria with additional constraints in the context of the Rwandan genocide: only those who saved lives but did not kill can be considered rescuers, reaffirming a criterion of moral absolutism, and denying the study of complex actors.",
  {'entities': [(7, 14, 'NORP'), (103, 110, 'NORP')]}),
("The University of Amsterdam and the University of Chicago provided me with a strong intellectual foundation for pursuing this research.",
  {'entities': [(3, 30, 'ORG'), (35, 60, 'ORG')]}),
("In my Master’s thesis, which was awarded the University of Amsterdam Faculty of Humanities Thesis Prize, I developed a historical analysis of rescuing during the Rwandan genocide.",
   {'entities': [(3, 24, 'WORK_OF_ART'), (44, 106, 'ORG'), (165, 172, 'NORP')]}),
("I used oral testimonies, memoirs, newspaper articles, and government-sponsored content to compare the reasons given for rescuing by Hutu rescuers, UN Commander Roméo Dallaire, humanitarian aid worker Carl Wilkens, and the Rwandan Patriotic Front.",
   {'entities': [(135, 139, 'PERSON'),(150, 152, 'ORG'),(163, 177, 'PERSON'),(203, 215, 'PERSON'),(221, 248, 'ORG')]}),
("I then wrote a peer-reviewed book chapter, forthcoming, which explored the constraints of the \"rescuer\" label (The Holocaust: Remembrance, Respect, Resilience, edited by Michael Posner and Suki John).",
   {'entities': [(118, 127, 'EVENT'),(173, 187, 'PERSON'),(192, 201, 'PERSON')]}),
("At UChicago, I delved into the history of human rights through the Human Rights minor with Susan Gzesh and Mark Bradley and engaged in the interdisciplinary discourse on mass violence through courses including \"Perpetrators, Victims, and Bystanders\" (Eric Stover) and \"Insurgency, Terrorism, and Civil War\" (Paul Staniland).",
   {'entities': [(6, 14, 'ORG'),(94, 105, 'PERSON'),(110, 122, 'PERSON'),(241, 251, 'PERSON'),(254, 265, 'PERSON'),(272, 293, 'WORK_OF_ART'),(299, 308, 'EVENT'),(311, 325, 'PERSON')]}),                      
("Through Harvard’s history study abroad program in Ghana (Emmanuel Akyeampong), I researched how the Middle Passage developed trauma-based communal identities.",
   {'entities': [(11, 18, 'ORG'), (53, 58, 'GPE'), (60, 79, 'PERSON')]}),
("Building on my coursework, my Bachelor’s thesis developed a historical analysis to evaluate early warning signs of genocidal events in Darfur.",
   {'entities': [(138, 144, 'GPE')]}),
("Arabic classes in high school and college and Arabic lessons with tutors, as well as an immersion course in Summer 2022, will enable me to study primary sources on rescuing in the Middle East.",
   {'entities': [(3, 9, 'NORP'),(49, 55, 'LANGUAGE'),(111, 122, 'DATE'),(179, 194, 'LOC')]}),
("My decision to pursue doctoral studies is also informed by my professional experiences at the Social Science Research Council (SSRC), J-PAL North America (MIT), and SYE Initiative and DAWNetwork.",
   {'entities': [(93, 128, 'ORG'),(137, 156, 'PERSON'),(158, 161, 'ORG'),(168, 182, 'ORG')]}),
("At the SSRC, I coordinated a fellowship that supports African PhD candidates studying peace and security.",
   {'entities': [(57, 64, 'NORP'), (65, 68, 'WORK_OF_ART')]}),
("At J-PAL North America, I coordinate fundraising, accruing $15 million to support randomized evaluations on poverty alleviation.",
   {'entities': [(12, 25, 'LOC'), (62, 73, 'MONEY')]}),
("As Program Manager at SYE Initiative, a nonprofit that helps Syrian and Iraqi students apply to college, and as founder of DAWNetwork, a mentorship program for Syrian girls, I fostered my interest in the Middle East and developed deep networks in both Syria and Iraq.",
   {'entities': [(3, 13, 'WORK_OF_ART'),(25, 39, 'ORG'),(64, 70, 'NORP'),(75, 80, 'NORP'),(126, 136, 'ORG'),(163, 169, 'NORP'),(203, 218, 'LOC'),(255, 260, 'GPE'),(265, 269, 'GPE')]}),
("The University of Notre Dame’s Peace Studies and History PhD is an ideal fit to pursue research on the creation and manipulation of rescuing narratives throughout the 20th century.",
   {'entities': [(3, 33, 'ORG'),(34, 47, 'ORG'),(60, 63, 'WORK_OF_ART'),(166, 182, 'DATE')]}), 
("I am a student of social policy, a civic engagement practitioner, a designer and an elite athlete (in fact, last time I visited Penn’s campus I was competing against your fencing team).",
   {'entities': [(131, 143, 'ORG')]}),
("The Master of Integrated Product Design program at University of Pennsylvania is an opportunity not only to deepen my design practice but to strengthen it through innovative engineering and clever business practices.",
   {'entities': [(3, 42, 'WORK_OF_ART'), (54, 80, 'ORG')]}),
("I am seeking opportunities to extend my tools for making a difference and I believe that the M:IPD program at Penn would do just that.",
   {'entities': [(98, 101, 'ORG'), (113, 117, 'ORG')]}),
("When I started my first quarter at Northwestern University all I knew was that I wanted to study something that would allow me to leverage my education for the betterment of communities.",
   {'entities': [(38, 61, 'ORG')]}),
("Eventually, I landed on Social Policy, a degree that would provide the opportunity to challenge systems and learn the methodologies necessary to improve those systems.",
   {"entities": []}),
("So, I pursued and completed two additional certificates: the Civic Engagement Certificate and the Design Certificate, both as a means of doing hands-on work to improve the lives of community members.",
   {"entities": []}),
("Much of my design work centers around accessibility. I seek to utilize design to increase access to experiences, products and opportunities.",
   {'entities': []}),        
("One community that I’m particularly moved by and interested in designing for, is that of aging or older adults.",
   {"entities": []}),
("A project in my portfolio, \"CareBot\" is an example of my work in this domain as it seeks to provide older adults with access to community, family, and empathetic medical care.",
   {'entities': [(31, 38, 'ORG')]}),
("In my time in the M:IPD program, I would be interested in continuing and expanding upon this focus.",
   {'entities': [(23, 26, 'ORG')]}),
("The engineering aspect of the program is especially interesting to me as I believe it would provide tangible means of innovation in order to bolster my aesthetic design work.",
   {'entities': []}),
("I know that courses such as \"Rehab Engineering & Design\" would be integral to leveraging engineering methodologies for creating real-world impact.",
   {'entities': [(32, 58, 'ORG')]})]   

